Contact

8349696661 (Mobile) ritikudawant12@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ritikudawant (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

B2B Marketing
Customer Satisfaction
Automotive Engineering

Languages

Marathi (Native or Bilingual) Hindi (Professional Working) English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Al Aware Badge - Al For All Al Appreciate Badge - Al For All

Publications

Desirability Function integrated Response Surface for CNC Milling Process Variables Optimization

Patents

DRAINAGE PIPES CLEANING ROBOT (Design Patent)

Ritik Laxmikant Udawant

The expert in anything was once a Mechanical Engineer. Durg, Chhattisgarh, India

Summary

I am a mechanical engineer with a passion for sales and customer service. I have one year of experience working as a sales officer at ITC Ltd., where I gained valuable experience in building relationships with customers and closing deals. I am currently working as an Assistant Manager Part Sales at Maruti Suzuki, where I am responsible for managing a team of Spare parts Managers & Operational Parts Manager for achieving sales targets for a portfolio of spare parts.

Experience

Maruti Suzuki India Limited Assistant Manager September 2023 - Present (9 months) Hyderabad, Telangana, India

ITC Limited

1 year 1 month

Instore Marketing (Trade Loyalty)
January 2023 - August 2023 (8 months)

Nagpur, Maharashtra, India

A results-oriented professional with a proven track record in driving targeted sales growth and optimizing merchandising strategies within the FMCG sector. Specializing in managing and expanding market presence across Maharashtra (Vidarbha, Marathwada, Khandesh regions) and Chattisgarh state, I have successfully overseen a network of 480 premium first club outlets, supermarkets & Shubh Labh wholesales, contributing approx 70% of the sales revenue in the Food & Personal Care in General trade channel.

- Expertly managed a team of 11 PMS vendor members, ensuring efficient merchandising practices and adherence to FIFO standards.
- Proficient in negotiating for prime window shelf space and promotional areas to enhance brand visibility and drive sales.

- Consistently achieved numeric and weighted distribution targets, while increasing product stacking and market penetration.
- Focused on ensuring product availability, visibility, and freshness to meet consumer demands and exceed expectations.
- Spearheaded the addition of new outlets to the first club network, orchestrating brand promotion activities and festival celebrations.
- Proficient in managing channel partners and leading cross-functional teams to achieve business objectives.
- Experienced in product launch initiatives, including product matrix development and performance tracking, ensuring successful market entry and sustained growth.
- -With a strategic mindset and hands-on approach, I thrive in dynamic environments, driving continuous improvement and delivering exceptional results. My dedication to excellence and passion for driving business growth make me a valuable asset to any organization.

Sales Trainee

August 2022 - December 2022 (5 months)

Nagpur, Maharashtra, India

Detailed understanding of the FMCG business Model & ITC Ltd overall FMCG business and the difference channel.

Understanding of the different channels of ITC Ltd.:

- Grocery one (GR1), Food
- Personal Care (GR2)
- Convenience focus product (CFP)

Gain knowledge of the range of product portfolio & the competition brand, using competition strategies & the implementation process.

Dealing with the channel partners & managing the team.

Launching of a product, the product matrix & tracking of the product growth was a wonderful experience.

South East Central Railways Engineering Trainee August 2021 - September 2021 (2 months)

Raipur, Chhattisgarh, India

- Assisted by the Head Mechanical engineering in the daily maintenance of railway engine wheels.
- Worked on the Project Report on the repair and maintenance of breaking system in diesel locomotive.
- Used Auto CAD as Assistant Design engineer under the guidance of design engineer for dimensioning CAD models.

Bhilai Steel Plant, SAIL Vocational training March 2021 - March 2021 (1 month) Bhilai, Chhattisgarh, India

- Under the guidance of the General Manager in the various departments learn basics daily routine and inspection in the plant.
- Worked with Capital Repair and Modification CRM department.
- Learn about the production of Rail & Plate in Rail mill, universal rail mill, Plate mill in the Plant.
- Learn about the various safety measures to be followed in the plant.
- Scheduling various meetings and presentation was a nice experience.

Education

Rungta College of Engineering & Technology Kohka-Kurud Bhilai. Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Mechanical Engineering